careerlauncher.com 2019-08-19

# Privacy Policy, Career Launcher

CL Educate ("CL Educate", "Career Launcher", "CLE", "CL", "we", "us" and "our") is committed to treating your personal information with respect and sensitivity. This document of Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") explains how we may collect, store, use, and disclose personal information when you ("you" or "User") access or use

(1) our websites located at www.cleducate.com or www.careerlauncher.com or www.careerlauncheruae.com and all of our other websites to which this Privacy Policy is posted (collectively, the "Website" or "Site");   
(2) our services, products, offerings & programs and courses ("Programs"); and   
(3) any services, content, and features made available by us through the Website or the Programs (together with the Website and the Programs, the "Services").

**YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

By accessing, registering, purchasing or using the Services, you signify that you have read, understood and agreed to be bound by the Privacy Policy in effect at the time of purchase and consent to our collection, storage, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. The provisions contained in this Privacy Policy supersede all previous notices and statements regarding our privacy practices with respect to the Services. If you do not agree to every provision of this Privacy Policy, you may choose not to access or use the Services. 

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time in our sole discretion, subject to applicable laws. When we undertake these revisions, we will post a revised version on the Website. The revised Privacy Policy will be effective upon posting on the Website, unless otherwise set forth therein or as otherwise required by applicable law. Since such changes shall apply to any purchases made after such changes are posted to the Site, you should review these terms prior to each registration / purchase so that you will understand the terms applicable to such transaction. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not make any purchases / register yourself on our Website. 

To reiterate, accepting this Privacy Policy, as and when revised, is required for your continued access and use of the Services. Except as otherwise expressly stated by us, your access and use of the Services are subject to the version of this Privacy Policy in effect at the time of your access or use of the Services.

**PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY AS THEY CONTAIN IMPORTANT INFORMATION REGARDING YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS, REMEDIES AND OBLIGATIONS. THESE ALSO INCLUDE VARIOUS LIMITATIONS AND EXCLUSIONS.**

**PURCHASE QUALIFICATION - ACCOUNT SECURITY**

To make a purchase on any of CL websites, you must comply with the terms set out in this Privacy Policy. You acknowledge that you are responsible for maintaining the security of, and restricting access to, your account and password, and you agree to accept responsibility for all purchases / registration and other activities that occur under your account. CL reserves the right to refuse or cancel orders at any time in its sole discretion.

**TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

When you use the Services, we may collect information that allows you to be identified (“Personal Data”), and we may also collect information that does not identify you (“Anonymous Information”). When Anonymous Information is, directly or indirectly, associated or combined with Personal Data, such Anonymous Information will be considered Personal Data for purposes of this Privacy Policy. In addition, to the extent Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses or similar identifiers or information are considered personally identifiable information by applicable law, we will treat such identifiers and information as Personal Data under this Privacy Policy.

**Information You Provide to Us:** In general, you may visit the Website without telling us who you are or sharing any Personal Data with us. However, if & when you register for an account for the Programs (an “Account”), and/or use other aspects of the Programs, and/or communicate with us for customer service or technical support for the Programs, we may ask you to provide certain Personal Data, such as your name, email address, postal address or telephone number, date of birth and gender.

You may decline to provide Personal Data to us, but, if you do so, certain Programs, or features of certain Programs, may not be available to you. For example, we sometimes request certain Personal Data to determine whether you are eligible for Services targeted toward particular cohorts. Sometimes, funders or sponsors of our Services require us to provide them with information regarding participants in these Services. Such information could include the contact information and program status of participants, which we would disclose to the funder or sponsor in the form of Personal Data, or the ethnicity, gender or other characteristics of participants, which we would disclose to the funder or sponsor in an aggregated form. In such cases, participation in the Services may be contingent on individuals providing the relevant Personal Data.

Only the person with the name with which you have enrolled will be allowed to access our [aspiration.ai](http://aspiration.ai/) platform and all the offerings that come with it. Also, only those documents which bear the same name will be validated.

If at any point of time we find out that your [aspiration.ai](http://aspiration.ai/) account or the content is being viewed or used by anyone else, we reserve the right to terminate your account without any prior intimation.

You can also be requested to mandatorily provide additional Personal Data to us, such as information pertaining to your educational background or personal and professional goals, or other geographical or demographic or biographical information,  admit card/score card for the exam that you are appearing in that particular target year which may or may not be associated with your Account.

We may ask you whether you want to receive human-controlled-and-operated calls and/or autodialed and prerecorded message calls and/or text messages relating to the Services. If you consent to such use of your phone number for these purposes, you may, if permissible under applicable laws and regulations, receive human-controlled-and-operated calls or autodialed and prerecorded message calls and/or text messages from us, as applicable, relating to the Services, at that number.

**Information Collected From Devices:** When you access the Services using a computer or mobile device, including a desktop computer, laptop, mobile phone, tablet, smart watch or other consumer electronic device (each, a “Device”), we may collect information from your Device, such as your Device type and manufacturer, your mobile carrier, your device software version, your Device identifiers, your mobile phone number, your IP address, your browser type, your network connection type, information about the webpage that referred you to the Website or that you visited prior to the Website, and your behavior and activity on the Website. Your behavior and activity on the Website may include the amount of time you spend using the Services and your login and log out times.

**Information Collected From Cookies and Similar Technologies:** When you access or use the Services, we may place small data files on your Device that assign random, unique numbers to your Device to enable us to recognize your Device when you use the Services. These data files may be cookies, pixel tags, other local shared objects, or similar technologies provided by your browser or associated applications (collectively, “Cookies”). We may use Cookies to recognize your Device, manage and store your settings and preferences for the Services, improve the Services, offer targeted products and services to you, and collect and analyze information about your use of the Services.

The Cookies we use in connection with the Services may include the following:

  * Session Cookies: Session Cookies are temporary Cookies that expire and are automatically erased when you close your browser window. We may use session Cookies to grant you access to content and to enable actions that require you to be logged into your Account to perform.
  * Persistent Cookies: Persistent Cookies are Cookies that usually have an expiration date in the distant future and remain in your browser until they expire or you manually delete them. We may use persistent Cookies to better understand usage patterns so we can improve the Services. For example, we may use a persistent Cookie to associate you with your Account or to remember your choices for the Services.
  * Third-Party Cookies: We may permit certain third parties to place Cookies through the Services to provide us with better insights into the use of the Services and user demographics and to provide relevant advertising to you. These third parties may use Cookies to collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use the Services. We may also allow third parties to display advertisements through the Services. These third-party advertisers may use Cookies to collect Anonymous Information. In some cases, we may have access to information from Cookies used by third-party advertisers through the Services, and this information may permit us to identify other websites or services that you have visited that are also associated with such third-party advertisers. The use of Cookies by third-party advertisers is subject to the respective third-party advertisers’ privacy policies.

By accessing or using the Services, you consent to the placement of Cookies on your Devices as described in this Privacy Policy. If you prefer not to receive Cookies through the Services, you may control how your browser responds to cookies by adjusting the privacy and security settings of your web browser. Unless you set your browser settings to refuse all Cookies, our system may issue Cookies when you access or use the Services. If you set your browser settings to refuse all Cookies, the performance of certain features of the Services may be limited or not work at all.

**Electronic Mail & URLs:** In some of our email messages to you, we may use “click-through URLs” linked to content on the Website. We track click-through data to help us understand and analyze interest in topics and use of the Services.

**Do Not Track:** Do Not Track (“DNT”) is an optional browser setting that allows you to express your preferences regarding tracking by advertisers and other third parties. We do not use technology that recognizes DNT signals from your web browser.

**Information Collected From Third Parties:** We also collect Personal Data about you from other companies. For instance, we may receive Personal Data about you from educational institutions, nominating partners, and third-party service providers.

**SPECIAL CATEGORIES OF PERSONAL DATA**

We do not & will not, unless you explicitly consent, process any Personal Data relating to you in the following special categories:   
(i) data revealing or concerning your racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, health, sex life or sexual orientation;   
(ii) genetic data; or, biometric data for the purpose of uniquely identifying you;

**HOW WE USE INFORMATION**

We may use Anonymous Information as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy and for research and commercial purposes, such as to improve the Services.  
We may use Personal Data for the purposes described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy and internally for our general commercial purposes, including, among other things, to:

  * Provide the Services and notices related thereto
  * Analyze, improve, and customize the Services
  * Provide customer and technical support for the Services
  * Send you announcements, newsletters, promotional materials, and other information about the Services and third-party products and services that we think may be of interest to you
  * Detect, prevent, and investigate actual or suspected fraud, hacking, infringement, or other misconduct involving the Services
  * Collect fees and other amounts owed in connection with the Services

We may use Personal Data in other ways that we expressly disclose at the time you provide it. We do not use your Personal Data to make automated decisions about you without any human input. In case, we ever begin to do so, if and as applicable, and to the extent required by applicable law, we will endeavor to implement suitable safeguards, including, for example, an opportunity for you to request human intervention, express your point of view, contest any decisions made, and request that we restrict the use of your personal data for the purposes of these automated decisions.

**HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION**

We may share Anonymous Information with third parties as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy and for our commercial purposes. We may share Personal Data for the purposes described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy and as follows:

  * If you request or authorize it
  * To complete a transaction or provide a service requested by you
  * To our third-party service providers that provide services on our behalf, such as payment processing, data analysis, e-mail delivery, hosting, order fulfillment, infrastructure, network storage, customer service, technical support, and promotional services
  * To comply with applicable laws, rules, and regulations and governmental and quasi-governmental requests, court orders, and subpoenas
  * To protect our rights, property, and safety or the rights, property, and safety of our users and others
  * If the disclosure is done as part of a purchase, transfer, or sale of services or assets (e.g., in the event that substantially all of our assets are acquired by another party, your Personal Data may be one of the transferred assets) or in the event of bankruptcy

**YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

You may opt not to receive promotional emails from us by contacting us as indicated below or by following the “unsubscribe” instructions in any promotional email you receive from us. Please note, however, that we may still send you non-promotional emails about your relationship with us.

You have the right to: 

(i) request confirmation of whether we store, use or share any of your personal data;   
(ii) obtain access to or a copy of your personal data;   
(iii) receive an electronic copy of personal data that you have provided to us, or ask us to send that information to another company (the “right of data portability”);   
(iv) restrict our uses of your personal data or object to those uses;   
(v) seek correction of inaccurate, untrue or incomplete personal data; or   
(vi) request erasure of personal data held about you by us, subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law.  
Where we are relying on consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. However, withdrawing consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at the email or physical address set out below. You will not have to pay a fee to exercise any of these rights. In addition, if you are a resident of the European Union, you have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority if you believe that your personal data has been collected or used in violation of relevant privacy requirements. We will retain Personal Data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by applicable law.

**INFORMATION YOU SHARE SOCIALLY**

The Services may allow you to connect and share your actions, comments, content, and information publicly or with other Program participants. We are not responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of any information you share publicly or with other Program participants. In addition, the Services may allow you to connect with us and share on third-party websites, applications, and services. Please be mindful of your personal privacy needs and the privacy needs of others, as you choose whom to connect with and what to share and make public. We cannot control the privacy or security of information you choose to make public or share with others. We also do not control the privacy practices of third parties. Please contact those websites and services directly if you want to learn about their privacy practices.

**HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

We have, and require, our third-party service providers to have administrative, technical, and physical safeguards in place in our respective computer systems, databases, and communications networks that are reasonably designed to protect information contained within such systems from loss, misuse, and alteration. The measures we utilize may include storing Personal Data on secured servers, transmitting Personal Data using encryption technologies, and auditing and reviewing our data collection practices. No method of electronic transmission or storage is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee absolute security of your Personal Data. You also play a role in protecting your Personal Data. Please safeguard your username and password for your Account and do not share them with others. If we receive instructions using your Account login information, we will consider that you have authorized the instructions. You agree to notify us immediately of any unauthorized use of your Account or any other breach of security related to the Services. We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to refuse to provide the Services, terminate your Account, and to remove or edit content.

**THIRD-PARTY LINKS**

When you use the Services, you may be directed to other websites and applications that are beyond our control. We may also allow third-party websites or applications to link to the Services. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any third parties or the content of linked websites and applications, but we do encourage you to read the applicable privacy policies and terms and conditions of such parties, websites, and applications. This Privacy Policy only applies to the Services.

**INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS**

Your Personal Data may be stored on computers and systems in India and/or other countries. By using the Services, you consent to the collection, transfer, processing, and storage of your Personal Data in such countries in the manner described in this Privacy Policy. You also acknowledge that the privacy laws of such countries may differ from the laws in the country where you are located and may not provide you the same rights or protections for your Personal Data.

**CONTACT US**

We have appointed a data protection officer who is responsible for overseeing questions related to this privacy policy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below. Our data protection officer may be reached at [gopi.r@careerlauncher.com](mailto:gopi.r@careerlauncher.com) or CL EDUCATE LIMITED, Attention: CMO, A-41, ESPIRE Building LGF, Mohan Industrial Cooperative Estate, Delhi-Mathura Road, New Delhi 110041, India.

**PURCHASE QUALIFICATION - ACCOUNT SECURITY**

To make a purchase on any of CL centers or websites, you must comply with the terms set out in this Terms of Sale. You acknowledge that you are responsible for maintaining the security of, and restricting access to, your account and password, and you agree to accept responsibility for all purchases / registration and other activities that occur under your account. CL reserves the right to refuse or cancel orders at any time in its sole discretion.

**PAYMENT METHODS & TERMS**

We currently accept the following forms of payment: Cash, Check (“payable at” locations will be advised by the Centers), Bank Drafts, Credit Cards (MasterCard, Visa, Discover, American Express - varies across Centers due to banking channel availability, hence do please check with the individual centers), Mobile Wallets, Bank Wire or Electronic Transfer (details available at the Centers)

**REFUNDS POLICY**

**Refund in case of incorrect purchase:** Programs purchased will not be refunded or changed to another program on grounds of incorrect selection at the time of purchase.

**Refund in case of server error:** In case the same program is purchased twice due to some server error, the following refund rules will apply - If the learner informs us within 7 days, full refund would be done thereafter he/she would be provided with a credit note, which is 10% more than the purchase value.

**Refund in case of special approval:** Refund is possible only if applied within 7 days of the purchase of the product and the max refund amount is 50% of the fee received. This is applicable across all the Programs except the Classroom Programs where it is dependent upon the center and its policy.

**TERMINATION**

**Termination by you:** You may, at any point in time, choose to terminate your subscription to a service by sending us an e-mail. Such termination will not change any amounts due to us.

**Termination by CL:** Breach of any of the terms of this Agreement constitutes a termination of the Agreement. Any and all amounts due under this Agreement shall survive the Term of this Agreement. If you fail, or CL suspects that you have failed, to comply with any of the provisions of this Agreement, including but not limited to failure to make payment of fees due, failure to provide CL with a valid credit card or with accurate and complete Registration Data, failure to safeguard your Account information, violation of the Usage Rules or any license to the software, or infringement or other violation of third parties' rights, CL, after notice of 07 (seven) days to rectify such failure to you, may terminate your subscription and/or your Account if such failure on your part still continues. No refunds will be issued in such a case of for early Termination.

**DATA USAGE**

The policy governing the data collection and usage in our centers and websites is detailed in our Privacy Policy.
